（昌文君(しょうぶんくん)）ふ… 不可能です 大王
我らが力は微弱
It... It's impossible, my king!
Our forces are feeble!
And now, without joining forces with Lü Shi or Jie Shi,
しかも今 秦国(しんこく)で―
呂氏(りょし) 竭氏(けつし)に くみせず
我らを助ける軍勢などありませぬ
there is no army in Qin that can help us!
Is that right?
（政(せい)）そうだろうか？
Do you have an idea, Zheng?
（信(しん)）何か手があるのか？ 政
あっ！ その吹き矢
あのおっさんのじゃねえかよ！
That blowgun!
Doesn't that belong to that old man?!
It doesn't matter! I got it now!
（貂(てん)）
いいじゃねえか　もらったんだよ！
（信）ちょっと見せろよ
Lemme see it for a sec!
（昌文君）アア… あった…
No! It's mine!
There is a way.
Did you say something, my lord?
（壁(へき)）
殿 何か おっしゃいましたか？
あ… あったぞ ひとつだけ
呂氏 竭氏に くみせぬ大軍勢が
Th-There is a way!
Just one...
A great army not joined with Lü Shi or Jie Shi!
I've been thinking about that since I arrived here.
ここに来たときから
俺も それを考えていた
The chances are low, but we have no choice but to go meet with them.
可能性は低いが
会いに行くしかない
The Mountain People,
山の民と 彼らを治める山の王に…
and the one who governs them, the Mountain King!
Ancient China.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）古代中国
聖者の時代は終わりを告げ
人間の欲望は解放されていた
After learning that the era of saints had ended,
human desire was unleashed.
And a storm of violent wars erupted for 500 years...
戦乱の嵐が
500年にわたって吹き荒れ
100を超えた国々は
７つに淘汰(とうた)された
until over one hundred states were reduced to merely seven.
そして今 西の果ての国 秦から―
And now, a wind of great history gusts from the state of Qin in the far West.
大いなる歴史が
生まれようとしている
これは
戦乱の時代を生き抜いた―
This is the tumultuous tale of a nameless boy and a young king who brought the warring era to its end!
名もなき少年と若き王の
激動の物語である
Presented by Anime-Destiny
Translation
kewl0210
itsumo yori hayaku kietetta hoshi zora ni
いつもより早く消えてった星空に
In a starry sky that disappeared faster than it ever has
kusanariatta deai wa
重なり合った出会いは
the many piled up meetings we've had
Editing
jagman1x3
ore wo nomikonde iku
俺を呑み込んでいく
swallow me.
kono yume wa kudakenai
この夢は砕けない
This dream cannot be broken.
Timing
Seboo
sabitsukaseta kyoufushin
錆びつかせた恐怖心
Among this rusted fear in my heart
yuragu fuan no naka de
揺らぐ不安の中で
and the anxiety that makes me waver
Typesetting
rtrs
ame wo saegiru shinjitsu
雨を遮る信実
is a truth that interrupts the rain.
dare ni mo ubaeyashinai
誰にも奪えやしない
No one can take it away,
Karaoke
kewl0210
FZeroWing
onaji keshiki ni hisonda puraido
同じ景色にひそんだプライド
our pride that lurks in the same landscape.
Encode
max80
itsuka kitto kanau ima mo mieru kibou fortitude
いつかきっと叶う 今も見える希望 fortitude
The fortuitous desire I have will definitely come true one day.
yowasa wo sute wa shinai
弱さを捨てはしない
We won't throw away our weaknesses,
oretachi no kienai shiin
俺達の消えないシーン
those are scenes that won't disappear.
furenzokusen no youni hashiru kibou unbreakable heart
不連続線の様に走る希望 unbreakable heart
My desire in my unbreakable heart runs like a discontinuitous line.
I knew at the start that there's no end.
QC
Mistral[sA]
KoolKidsK
I've made up my mind, right now it's the time to take the first step.
Distro
kokus
Kittie
prefix-
Qpax
Now's the only time.
～♪
The Terrifying Mountain People
（貂）ハァハァ… ねえねえ 政！
Hey, hey, Zheng!
（貂）ンッ… 山の王なんて
俺 聞いたことなかったけど
I've never heard of a Mountain King,
それって 山の中にも
秦国みたいな国があって
but by that, you mean there's a country in the mountains with a king, like the State of Qin?
王さまが いるってことなのか？
No, not quite.
いや それとは少し意味が違う
As you know, the Mountain People live in separate tribes,
お前も知っているように―
山の民は
部族ごとに分かれて暮らしているが
but because it mutually benefits them all, they've also formed an alliance.
全体の利益のために
同盟を結ぶこともあるという
The one who represents that alliance and leads it is the one we call the Mountain King.
その同盟を代表し 指導する者が
俺たちの言う“山の王”だ
（信）おい 政！
（貂）うん？
Hey, Zheng.
遅れ始めたヤツがいるぜ
Some guys've started to fall behind.
ハァ… ハァ…
お前ら グズグズすんな！
散歩に来たんじゃねえんだぞ！
Quit lagging behind, you guys!
We're not out for a walk!
Wh-What're you talking about, Xin?!
（壁）
な… なんてことを言うんだ 信！
我らが どれだけ疲れているか
知りもしないで
Don't you have any idea how exhausted we are?!
知るか！ 遅(おせ)えもんは遅え！
Like I care!
If you're slow, you're slow!
If you keep dragging your feet, that Chengjiao bastard's gonna end up as king!
グズグズしてたら―
成蟜(せいきょう)とかいう野郎が
王さまになっちまうぜ！
クッ… 小僧め…
Damn youngster...
But we do need to hurry...!
だが 今は急がねば
We need to have our king meet the Mountain King as soon as possible!
一刻も早く 我が王を
山の王に引き合わせるのだ
And also...
それに…
追っ手が残っているやもしれぬ
there may still be pursuers!
Stay vigilant!
（小隊長）気を抜くな！
竭丞相(じょうしょう)のご期待は
ただならぬものがある
Chancellor Jie has the highest of expectations for us!
We must find that boy, no matter where he may be!
少年を
なんとしても発見せねば―
どんな処分があるか分からんぞ
（兵士たち）はっ！
Yes, sir!
（小隊長）ハァ…
（斬る音）
ウワッ！
（兵士たち）アアッ！
（小隊長）なに？
What?!
ウワッ！
Ma-Majiu Soldiers...
ま… 馬酒兵(ましゅへい)？
わあ！
（貂）うわぁ… す～ごい眺めだ！
What a great view...
それにしても 政…
But anyhow, Zheng,
こんな山の中で どうして
山の王の城へ行く道が分かるの？
how do you know the way to the Mountain King's castle all the way out here in the mountains?
Duke Mu's summer retreat was made by the Mountain People, directly in between the capital of Qin, Xianyang, and the Mountain King's castle.
穆公(ぼくこう)の避暑地は―
秦国の都 咸陽(かんよう)と 山の王の城との
中間に作られたものだ
だから おおよその方角が分かるし
So I know the general direction it's in.
If we rely on the occasional landmarks we see on the way, we should reach the Mountain King's castle.
時々 現れる目印を頼りに行けば
山の王の城に たどりつくはずだ
（貂）ふ～ん…
（信）なるほど
I get it...
（兵士Ｂ）ハァ… アアッ…
Hey! Pull yourself together!
（兵士Ａ）おい しっかりしろ！
What happened?!
うん？ 何だ何だ？
I... I'm all right.
だ… 大丈夫だ
Someone lend him a shoulder.
誰か肩を貸してやれ
（昌文君）ならぬ
（壁）うん？
No!
ついてこられぬ者は下山して
穆公の避暑地で待機せよ
Those who cannot keep up can descend the mountain and wait at Duke Mu's summer retreat!
My lord?
（壁）殿…
Understand, everyone?!
よいか？ 皆の者
進軍を遅らせる者は―
Be fully aware that anyone who delays our march...
should immediately withdraw!
直ちに離脱させる旨
肝に銘じておけ！
P-Please, wait!
お… お待ちを！
そんなことをしては―
If we do that, most of our members will soon withdraw!
この先
ほとんどの者が離脱してしまいます
We have no choice.
しかたがない
信が言うように
成蟜が王位に就いてしまえば―
As Xin said,
if Chengjiao takes the throne, everything will be for naught!
全てがムダになってしまう
We must hurry!
急がねばならんのだ
But then we'll have no one left to guard the king!
しかし それでは
王を守る者が いなくなります
Against these terrifying Mountain People,
あの恐ろしい山の民を
相手にするには―
we need every soldier we can get to protect the king!
１人でも多くの兵で
王をお守りせねば
Terrifying?
恐ろしい？
If the Mountain People were to seriously attack us,
山の民が
本気で我らを攻撃してきたら…
we wouldn't stand a chance whether everyone were here or not!
ここにいる皆が いようが いまいが
ひとたまりもないわ
Hang on, what do you mean "terrifying Mountain People"?!
（信）ちょっと待てよ！
“恐ろしい山の民”って 何だよ？
Aren't those Mountain People... the ones who protected Duke Mu 400 years ago?
山の民って あの穆公ん家(ち)を
400年も守ってきた―
They sounded like pretty nice guys.
なんか
いいヤツらじゃねえのかよ？
I see. You two don't know the story of the Majiu Soldiers.
そうか…
君たちは知らないのか
“馬酒兵”の話を…
Majiu Soldiers?
馬酒兵？
( Flags - Qin )
It was 400 years ago...
（壁）今から400年ほど前…
The broad-minded king of our State of Qin...
我が秦国の王は―
gave liquor to the Mountain People who had eaten a horse he owned.
王が所有する馬を
食べてしまった山の民に―
酒を振る舞うほど心の広い王だった
I know! That's Duke Mu, ain't it?!
（信）知ってるぜ 穆公だろう
Yes. It was the 13th year Duke Mu had been king.
（壁）そうだ
その穆公が王になって13年目だ
( Flags - Jin )
There had been a country called Jin that was then separate from our country.
かつて
我が国とは別の晋国(しんこく)があった
A separate country called Jin?
（信）別の晋国？
（壁）ああ
Yes.
At the time, that State of Jin, which extended to the east of our State of Qin,
当時 我が秦国の東に広がっていた
その晋国が大飢饉(だいききん)に見舞われた
was undergoing a severe famine.
It was an enemy state, but to save the people suffering from hunger,
敵対していた国だったが
飢えに苦しむ人々を救うため―
Duke Mu sent them food supplies.
穆公は食糧を送った
Oh! I knew that Duke Mu would come through!
（信）オオッ！ さすが穆公だぜ
However, the next year, it was Qin that suffered from a massive famine.
（壁）ところが その次の年 今度は
我が秦国が大飢饉に見舞われた
When Duke Mu then sought aid,
そこで 穆公が援助を求めると…
Jin invaded our country.
晋は 我が国を侵略すべく
攻め込んできたのだ
Huh?! How the hell could they do that?!
ええっ？ そんなの ありかよ？
This, of course, enraged Duke Mu as well,
（壁）
これには さすがの穆公も激怒し
and he sent in his own troops to fight them.
自ら 先陣に立って戦った
But with the lack of food supplies due to the famine,
しかし 飢饉のため―
ロクに食糧もなかった我が秦国の
兵士たちは しだいに 力を失い
our Qin soldiers lost strength,
and Jin's army surrounded Duke Mu.
穆公は
晋の大軍に包囲されてしまったのだ
（信）アア… やっべえ！
やべえじゃねえか 穆公！
Oh no! That's really bad, Duke Mu!
It was truly a desperate situation.
（壁）正に絶体絶命だった
But at that moment... they appeared!
しかし そのとき 現れたんだ
The people we've traditionally called the "Majiu Soldiers"...
（壁）我らが“馬酒兵”と呼び
語り伝えてきた者たち…
300 Mountain People enveloped by a strange thirst for blood.
異様な殺気に包まれた300人の
山の民が…
Mountain People?
（信）山の民が？
（貂）どうして？
Why?!
They had incurred a debt towards Duke Mu.
穆公に受けた恩を返しに来たのだ
馬と酒の恩を返しに
The debt of the horse and the liquor.
I get it. So that's why they're called the Majiu Soldiers!
( Majiu - Horse Liquor )
そうなのか それが馬酒兵か！
So what's the deal? They really are incredible, then!
なんだよ　やっぱ
すげえいいヤツらじゃねえかよ
It's true that they have a profound sense of gratitude.
義理に厚いのは確かだ　しかし…
But...
the Majiu Soldiers' way of fighting...
（壁）馬酒兵の戦いぶりは
味方された我が秦国の兵士たちも
was said to be so ferocious that it struck fear even into the Qin soldiers, their allies.
恐怖を感じるほど
凶暴なものだったという
What's more, with just 300 people,
（壁）
しかも 彼らは たった300人で―
they drove out several thousand enemy soldiers.
数千の敵兵を蹴散らし
After saving Duke Mu,
穆公を救ったあと
敵の王を捕らえてしまった
they captured the enemy king.
The Mountain People are a ferocious warrior tribe.
山の民は恐ろしい戦闘民族なのだ
Even if they did protect Duke Mu's summer retreat,
穆公の避暑地を
守っているからといって―
to think that the people of Qin have the favor of the Mountain People is naive.
山の民が 我々 秦国の人間に好意を
持っていると考えるのは安直だ
Far from it, since we unilaterally ceased interacting with them after the death of Duke Mu...
むしろ 穆公の死後
一方的に交流をやめた我々を―
it would be more natural to think that they hate us.
憎んでいると考えたほうが
自然かもしれない
Those are the kind of people whose world we're stepping into without permission.
そんな彼らの世界に 我々は
無断で足を踏み入れているのだ
Do you know what what will happen if we're seen as enemies?!
もし 敵と見なされたら
一体 どうなるか…
Got it.
（信）分かったぜ　山の民が
どんなに恐ろしいヤツらか―
I totally understand just how terrifying the Mountain People are.
よ～く分かった
（壁）分かったか　だからこそ…
Do you?
That's why...
That's why they're worth allying ourselves with!
だからこそ
味方にする値打ちがある！
Don't you think so, Zheng?
そういうことだろう？ 政
That's right.
そういうことだ
（貂）あっ！
政が１人で もう あんなとこに！
Zheng already went that far on his own?!
Hey! Hold up, Zheng!
（信）おい！ 待てよ 政！
Even though I've become a civil officer,
（昌文君）
文官になったとはいえ―
and I've planned to serve actively in the military for quite some time,
まだまだ
現役の武人のつもりであったが…
age is a fearsome thing.
年老いるとは怖いものだな
But this is not the time to spout complaints!
だが
弱音を吐いている場合ではない！
The only one who can be that man's sword is me!
あのお方の剣となれるのは
わしひとり！
It's not something he can do.
あやつにはムリだ
気性が まっすぐすぎる
His temperament is too straightforward.
By simple laws of martial arts, he cannot cut through this world of warring states...
単純な武芸だけで この戦国の世を
切り開くことはできぬ
I am truly the only one who can!
やはり わししか…
ハッ… なに？
What?
Mountain People?!
（政）山の民か？
They came out!
（貂）出た！
Protect the king!
王をお守りしろ！
王を中心に円陣を組むのだ！
Form a circle around the king!
Stay calm!
騒ぐな！
If they felt like it, they'd have attacked us long ago.
彼らが その気なら
とっくに襲われているはずだ
じゃ お出迎えに来たってのか？
Then they just came to meet us?
They've sure got some dangerous stuff for doing that!
それにしちゃ 物騒な物(もん)持ってるぜ
This is our world.
（バジオウ）ここは我々の世界だ
He speaks...
俺たちの言葉を…
（貂）しゃべった！
Our language?!
When the Flatland People enter on their own,
（バジオウ）
平地の民が勝手に入ってきた場合
we gouge out both eyes and drop them from a waterfall.
両目をえぐって 滝に落とす
But you all have come to meet our king.
だが お前たちは
我らの王に会いに来た
会いに来た理由によって
どうするか決める
We will decide what to do depending on your reason.
How do you know we're here to meet the Mountain King?!
なぜ我々が
山の王に会いに来たことを…
Our king knows all.
我らの王は 何でも知っている
Our king is awaiting the State of Qin's young King.
秦国の若き王よ
我らの王がお待ちだ
We will take you to the King's castle.
お前を王の城まで連れていく
What?! You should've said so sooner!
なんだよ
それなら 話が早(はえ)えじゃねえか
Okay, let's get going!
さあ とっとと行こうぜ！ ヘヘッ…
ウッ… ウワッ…
（バジオウ）ンンッ！
ウワーッ！
ウウッ… いってえ…
（貂･壁）信！
Ow...
Xin!
What the hell're you doing?!
何しやがる てめえ！
Do not misunderstand.
勘違いするな
We will bring the king alone.
連れていくのは 王ひとりだけだ
ほかは今すぐ下山しろ
You others must descend the mountain now.
（どよめき）
（昌文君）な… なんだと？
Wh-What did you say?!
ンンッ… “イヤだ”っつったら？
And if we say no?!
We will kill... you all.
全員 殺す
Hurry. We have a bloodthirsty group assembled here today.
（バジオウ）早くしろ
今日は 血の気の多いヤツらが
集まっている
（戦士Ｂ）ハアーッ！
We've heard what you have to say.
お前らの言い分は分かったぜ
次は こっちの言い分だ！
Now here's what we've got to say!
If you guys don't wanna be slaughtered,
お前らこそ
皆殺しに されたくなかったら―
hurry up and bring us to your king!
俺たちを王の所まで
とっとと連れていきやがれ！
うりゃー！
Wait!
待て！
Both parties, put away your weapons.
双方 武器を収めろ
山の民の要求どおり
俺ひとりで山の王に会いに行く
As per the Mountain People's demands, I will go to meet the Mountain King alone.
Please wait! We could never descend the mountain, leaving our king alone!
お待ちください
王おひとりを残して下山するなど…
全員 下山して 俺が戻るのを待て
All of you, go down the mountain and wait for my return!
This is an order from your king!
これは王の命令だ！
Hey, Zheng!
（信）おい 政！
You want me to go down the mountain, too?
俺も下山させるのか？
俺は
お前の剣じゃなかったのかよ？
Aren't I your sword?
I don't need a sword for a discussion.
話し合いに 剣は必要ない
Do what you want.
勝手にしろ
General Wang Qi!
（伝令）王騎(おうき)将軍！
A message from Chancellor Jie has come appointing you as the commanding officer defending Hangu Pass, General.
（伝令）竭丞相より―
将軍を函谷関(かんこくかん)の守備隊長に
任命するという指令が届きました
（王騎）“受け身は
趣味じゃないの”ってお断りなさい
Decline, telling him "I have no interest in being passive."
Yes, sir.
Hangu Pass, eh?
函谷関ですか…
Lü Buwei
Wei
Hangu Pass
Jie Shi
Qin
Hangu Pass is an important barrier protecting Qin's Eastern border.
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）函谷関は 秦国の東の
守りの要となる重要な関所である
Lü Buwei
Wei
Hangu Pass
Jie Shi
Qin
To prevent Lü Shi's army, on campaign in the State of Wei,
魏(ぎ)の国に
遠征している呂氏たちの軍が―
from returning to Qin,
秦国に戻るのを防ぐためには―
Jie Shi must hold Hangu Pass.
竭氏たちは この函谷関を
押さえておかなければならない
It would seem that Jie Shi and Lü Shi have begun preparations for all-out war.
竭氏は 呂氏と全面的に戦う準備を
始めたようですねえ
王のいない所で
事が動きだしましたか…
It would seem things have gotten active with the king gone...
To take center stage in this situation would be no easy task.
（王騎）こうなると
表舞台に戻るのは至難の業ですよ
ねえ？ 騰(とう)
Isn't that right, Teng?
Yes. Quite a difficult task.
（騰）はっ… 至難の業です
Ying Zheng...
嬴政(えいせい)…
いわくつきの生まれの 不運の王…
An unlucky king whose birth has a shady history.
King Zheng will...
政さまは 昭王(しょうおう)を超えるぞ！
surpass King Zhao!
（王騎）ふ～ん… フフッ…
How he will surpasses King Zhao, a man who was even called the God of War,
戦神(いくさがみ)とまで いわれた あの昭王を
どう超えるというのか…
is something I'd very much like to see.
見せていただきたいものですねえ
The king is concerned for us, so he went alone.
（壁）王は 我らのことを気遣って
おひとりで行かれたのだ
But they even invited Zheng, for now.
でも 政は一応 招待されたんだし…
大丈夫だよね？
Won't he be okay?
That's not what you call inviting him.
あれは“招待”とはいわない
“拉致”だ
It's taking him captive.
He's... gonna get killed.
あいつ 殺されるな
Hey! Don't just say that like it's nothing!
（貂）お前な
そういうこと 簡単に言うなよ！
He's definitely gonna get killed.
（信）絶対 殺される
（貂）もう！
Hey!
Geez, who the hell said "Let's make friends with the Mountain People"?
…たく 誰だよ！
“山の民を味方に
つけよう”なんて言ったのは
（貂）ヒャッ！ アア…
ヤーッ！
（信）ウワッ…
What the hell are you doing, bastard?!
何しやがる てめえ！
クッ… こ… この！
Y-You...
Are you crazy, old man?!
血迷ったか おっさん！
（信）フン！ おっさんが
脚を痛めてんのは知ってたぜ
I knew your leg was wounded, old man!
My lord! What on earth got into you?!
殿！ 一体 どうされたのです？
Go, Xin.
行け 信
I hate to admit it... but you're more useful than I am right now.
悔しいが…
今のわしより
お前のほうが役に立つ
Follow the king, please!
王を追ってくれ 頼む
Lord is... bowing his head to someone other than the king.
（壁）殿が 王以外の人間に
頭を下げておられる…
しかも 名もない下僕の少年に…
And what's more... it's to a nameless servant boy.
No point bowing your head, old man.
（信）
頭下げるだけムダだぜ おっさん
Zheng said "I don't need a sword for a discussion."
政は“話し合いに
剣は要らない”って言ったんだ
Which means, if his discussion doesn't go well,
…ていうことは 話し合いが
うまくいかなかったら―
he will need a sword, right?
剣が要るってことだろう？
フッ… だから もともと―
That's why, in the first place, I was waiting for Zheng to get a head start before I went after him.
俺は 時間を置いて
政のあとを追うつもりだったんだ
I see.
そうか… では 早く行け バカ者
Then hurry up and go... you idiot.
（信）う… うるせえな！ 今行くよ
Shut up! I'm going!
Wait for me in Duke Mu's house and get your leg healed up! See ya!
穆公ん家で
脚を治しながら待ってろよ！
じゃあな！
Wait! I'm going, too!
待てよ 俺も行く！
Xin!
（昌文君）信！
（信）何だよ？ しつけえな
What? Don't you ever give it a rest?
I'm sorry about Piao.
（昌文君）
漂(ひょう)のことは すまなかった
It wasn't supposed to go this way...
こんなはずではなかった
Forgive me.
許せ
I'm leaving the king to you!
（昌文君）王を頼む！
（信）ああ…
Right.
kowaresou na kokoro tsumugu youni
壊れそうな心 紡ぐように
To weave together my breaking heart
yume no kakera mitsume (No more cry)
夢のカケラ見つめ (No more cry）
I gaze at the fragments of a dream (No more crying)
me no mae ni wa tsuki ga utsushidasu
目の前には月が映し出す
The moon I see before my eyes
kono mune no yakusoku
この胸の約束
reflects this promise in my heart
namida ga nokoshita kioku sae mo
涙が残した記憶さえも
I won't turn away from my tearful memories
～♪
waraiatta kako sae furimukanai
笑いあった過去さえ振り向かない
nor the past where we laughed together
（信）お前の道って 一体 何だ？
Voice of soul
（ﾅﾚｰﾀｰ）
血塗られた怨念の歴史を背負い
Voice of you
kanashimi nara kitto tsuyosa ni kawaru hazu
悲しみならきっと 強さに変わるはず
Sadness is sure to turn into strength
今 ２人の王が対峙(たいじ)する
次回 “それぞれの夢”
I won't cry
I won't fear
I won't stop
takaku tobeba kitto sora no mukou ni todoku
高く翔べばきっと空の向こうに届く
If I jump high enough, I'm sure I'll reach beyond the sky
Voice of mine
Yeah
Voice of soul
Preview
What the hell is your path?!
Bearing histories smeared with blood,
now, the two kings confront each other!
Each One's Dream
Next time,
End
Each One's Dream